Todor Tochev

R3.17, Paris School of Economics 48 boulevard Jourdan 75014 Paris France tstochev@gmail.com ttochev.github.io

+336 75 33 07 03

Economist working on the evaluation of public policies with a focus on labour markets and public assistance programmes. Speciality in applied causal inference and econometrics with big datasets. Experienced in using R, Stata, Python, Julia, SQL to analyse administrative datasets, internal company databases, and surveys.

RESEARCH SKILLS

Microeconometrics: Causal Inference, Randomized Control Trials, Difference-in-Differences, Regression Discontinuity Design, Bunching.

Big Data: Analysed employment, vocational training and fiscal databases covering country-size populations (400+ million observations).

Project management: As Principal Investigator, directed a team of 10+ research assistants coordinating data collection, transcription, cleaning and analysis.

Data collection: Survey questionnaire design and programming for hand-held devices and websites, web analytics, acquisition and cleaning of company operational databases.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. Economics, University of Warwick, 2023. Dissertation title: Essays in Applied Microeconomics

MRes. Economics, University of Warwick, 2018 (Distinction)
MSc. Economics, University of Warwick, 2014 (Distinction)
BSc. Business Administration, University of Bath, 2011

RESEARCH

Credit Constraints and Training Subsidies for Job-Seekers: Evidence from France

Take-up of Social Programs: Experimental Evidence from France, joint with Laura Castell, Marc Gurgand and Clément Imbert, Conditionally accepted at American Economic Journal: Economic Policy

Do Localised Lockdowns Cause Labour Market Spillovers?, joint with Gabriele Guaitoli

Returns to Adult Vocational Education for Job-Seekers: Evidence from a Regression Discontinuity Design (work in progress)

Effect of Pension Age Reforms on End-of-career Labour Market Participation, joint with Maxime Tô (work in progress)

WORK EXPERIENCE

2024-	Senior Economist, Institut des Politiques Publiques
2018-	Visiting Researcher, Dares, Ministry of Labour (Paris, France)
2023-24	Postdoctoral Fellow, Paris School of Economics (Paris, France)
2014-16	Research Associate, JPAL Europe (Paris, France)

Work on randomized evaluations: coordination with stakeholders, data collection and analysis.

Projects in education, public, and development economics.

2014 Research Assistant, University of Warwick

Cleaning large fiscal datasets and estimation of taxable income elasticities.

2011-12 Business Analyst, Astra Asset Management (Sofia, Bulgaria)

Portfolio analysis and regulatory compliance.

COMPUTER SKILLS

Programming: R, Stata, Python, Julia, SAS, SQL **Questionnaire administration**: ODK, SurveyCTO

OS: Windows, Linux

GRANTS AND AWARDS

2022 Covid Academic Support Fund PhD Grant (Royal Economic Society)

2021 Fondation du Risque, Chaire Sécurisation des Parcours Professionels Grant Award (€100,000, PI)

2018–22 ESRC Collaborative Studentship (University of Warwick & Ministry of Labour of France)

2011 L'Oréal Prize for Best Performing Student in Business and the Natural Environment (University of Bath)

LANGUAGES

English (fluent), French (fluent), Bulgarian (native), German (basic)

REFERENCES

Clément Imbert

Professor of Economics Sciences Po (Paris) clement.imbert@sciencespo.fr

Roland Rathelot

Professor of Economics CREST, ENSAE roland.rathelot@ensae.fr

Marc Gurgand

PSE Chaired Professor & Head of Economics Department ENS-PSL Paris School of Economics marc.gurgand@psemail.eu